Rasha Moumneh

732-789-9662 | rasha@rasha.dev | linkedin.com/in/rashamoumneh | github.com/rashamou | Philadelphia, PA

Summary

I'm a customer-centric, collaborative fullstack developer with 2+ years of experience. I have a passion for writing tools to make it easier for my colleagues to do their work. My favorite projects to build are ones where my work improves everyone's lives without them really even noticing. I love learning new technologies and enjoy writing maintainable, testable code that adheres to good design practices and processes.

SKILLS

Languages: Perl, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js

Frameworks and Tools: React, NextJS, Django, ExpressJS, SQLAlchemy, Unix, Git, Agile, Scrum, Tailwind

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite

Other: REST APIs, Email protocols (IMAP, JMAP, SMTP, SPF, DKIM, DMARC)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Fastmail (Philadelphia, PA)

Jan 2023 - June 2024

- Wrote and deployed backend in Perl for advanced email address management features through user-defined rules in Fastmail's email app
- Built RESTful APIs to integrate external services with Fastmail's web app, expanding functionality and user interactivity
- Integrated video conferencing capabilities into Fastmail's calendar app
- · Designed and implemented a referral program tied to the billing system, boosting user acquisition and revenue growth
- Built a library to optimize mass communication processes with customers, enabling targeted user segmentation and efficient tracking
 of engagement metrics
- Led a refactoring initiative to simplify codebase and expand test coverage for Fastmail's email alias feature to improve maintainability and adherence to coding best practices

Support Engineer

Fastmail (Philadelphia, PA)

Oct 2020 - Jan 2023

- · Triaged bug reports to prioritize and allocate resources, ensuring critical issues were addressed promptly
- · Built internal tools in Perl for the support team to aid in ticket troubleshooting, significantly reducing customer response time
- · Investigated and resolved software bugs reported by users, improving system stability and user satisfaction

Customer Support Agent

Fastmail (Philadelphia, PA)

Apr 2019 – Sep 2020

- · Diagnosed, troubleshot, and resolved customer issues
- · Wrote customer facing product documentation

Software Engineer Intern

Academic Analytics (Remote)

Sep 2020 - Oct 2020

- Built data-heavy front-end of funding forecast application using React
- · Developed RESTful APIs using Node.js and Express with a MySQL database

Software Engineer (Contract)

Key Conservation (Remote)

May 2020 – Jul 2020

- · Wrote onboarding feature for nature conservation social media app in React Native and Node.js
- · Led backend migration from AirTable to PostgreSQL database
- · Designed and built admin dashboard

Program Coordinator & Instructor

Rutgers University (New Brunswick, NJ)

- · Developed global campaign communications strategy for the Center for Women's Global Leadership
- · Designed and taught in-person and online undergraduate courses in gender studies

Sep 2013 - Mar 2019

Researcher 2009 – 2013

Human Rights Watch (New York, NY - Beirut, Lebanon)

- · Conducted investigative research on human rights abuses in Lebanon, Tunisia, Iraq, and Egypt
- · Produced reports, press releases, and briefing papers

Campaign Coordinator

Kafa (Beirut, Lebanon)

· Launched and coordinated multi-year campaign that resulted in Lebanon's first anti-domestic violence law

2007 - 2009

PROJECTS & VOLUNTEER WORK

Igor (Python / NodeJS) I GitHub Python I GitHub Node.js

Igor is an extensible multi-platform chatbot framework for automated interactions across various messaging platforms in two programming languages. The system features a modular architecture employing observer, factory, adapter, and command design patterns. It has a central hub coordinating platform-specific channel adapters (Discord, Telegram, Console) with customizable reactors for processing user commands and generating responses. It uses event-driven communication, asynchronous processing, and a plugin system using the strategy pattern for easy feature expansion.

Philly Farmer's Markets (NextJS, Leaflet.js, ArcGIS REST API, TailwindCSS) | GitHub | Live site

A responsive web application for locating and displaying information about Philadelphia farmers' markets. Integrated ArcGIS REST API for real-time market data. Features include an interactive map, search functionality, and filters for markets currently open. Mobile-first design with Tailwind CSS for optimal viewing across devices.

The Feed-o-tron (Vanilla JS, Typescript, Express, TailwindCSS, GPT-3.5) I GitHub I Live site

A full stack web application that automatically converts any website into a structured RSS feed through intelligent content analysis. It features a dynamic interface that allows users to visually map webpage elements to RSS fields with real-time preview capabilities. Implemented advanced HTML parsing and content extraction algorithms using Cheerio, with fallback to GPT-3.5 analysis for complex page structures.

Prometheus (NextJS/TypeScript, TailwindCSS, Redis)

(In Progress) A responsive web application for clients of the Family Justice Center of Washington County to learn about local services available to them. Users fill out a multi-step form whose answers are mapped on to a list of relevant services. City data is tracked using Redis, and FJCWC accesses these analytics via a password protected dashboard where they can optionally download the data as a CSV.

EDUCATION

Bloom Institute of Technology Full Stack Web Development Rutgers University, New Brunswick MPhil Gender Studies University College London MA Social Anthropology American University of Beirut BA Psychology